ANDREW FORD

+64211197491

me@andrewford.co.nz <u>LinkedIn</u> Matua, Tauranga New Zealand

Profile

Passionate about the web industry, I am an organised, motivated individual who takes personal ownership of projects to deliver exceptional results. As a collaborative leader, I enjoy mentoring team members and constantly learning new techniques, software, tools, and workflows. Check out my blog at www.andrewford.co.nz for my insights and experiences.

Experience

Head of Teaching, Developers Institute, Whangarei (Remote) — 2023-Present

Implementing evidence-based pedagogy practices and building capability to ensure high-quality and consistent teaching practices. Skilled in coaching, mentoring, and providing support for instructors, identifying personal development opportunities, and improving the experience for learners. Strong leadership abilities, with experience leading teams involved in program development and delivery. Accountable for the delivery of the program on time and meeting all deadlines for curriculum development, assessments, and grading.

Tech Lead / Instructor, Developers Institute, Whangarei (Remote) — 2021-2023

Web development instructor with expertise in Full-Stack and Client-Side web development teaching, which includes CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Unit Testing (with Jest), NodeJS, and ReactJS. Proven track record of preparing lessons, creating assignments and learning materials, and conducting code reviews to ensure students have the tools they need to become top-notch developers. Strong commitment to student success, ensuring they are on track to achieve their goals.

Senior Developer, Craigs Investment Partners, Tauranga — 2020-2021

Experienced senior developer specialising in bespoke web apps, including a cutting-edge investment trading platform for individuals to buy and sell securities. Integral member of a dynamic SCRUM team of 7, working with ReactJS, Redux, GatsbyJS, TypeScript, .Net Core (C#), and Azure. Additionally, provided expert mentorship to junior developers.

Lead Developer, QJumpers, Tauranga — 2017-2020

Lead developer overseeing a small, high-performing team of 3, with a focus on managing the agile SCRUM process and conducting performance reviews. Spearheading the development of an innovative Applicant Tracking System for the NZ and USA markets, hosted on AWS across multiple regions. Utilising cutting-edge technologies such as Docker, Kubernetes, React JS, .Net Core, and Postgres to create a seamless user experience.

Software Engineer, Datacom, Tauranga — 2015-2017

Lead front end developer driving the development of a SaaS cloud-based ERP for local government on Azure. Successfully led the team's transition from Angular to TypeScript and ReactJS, championing the adoption of cutting-edge technologies. Utilising an agile SCRUM process to ensure seamless collaboration and timely delivery of the project.

Senior Software Engineer, Monitor Business Machines, Auckland (Remote) – 2014-2015

Lead developer on the development of a dynamic mobile hybrid app for Android & iOS, enabling account top-ups for cashless POS via multiple payment gateways. Built on a robust software stack utilising ASP.Net Web API and AngularJS, ensuring a seamless user experience.

Senior Front End Developer, Terabyte Interactive, Auckland (Remote) — 2012-2014

Senior front end developer working on multiple marketing websites built on Umbraco CMS for multiple NZ industries including tourism, agriculture and government.

Full Stack Web Developer, SpeEDI Software, Tauranga — 2011-2012

Design and development of a SaaS global freight and customs management web application for Custom Brokers, Freight Forwarders, Shipping Lines & Agents, Exporters and Importers. Built using ASP .Net MVC on Microsoft Azure cloud hosting.

Front End Team Leader, Cucumber Software, Tauranga — 2006-2011

Mentoring a team of 3 other developers. Researching and instructing the front end team in best practice and process. Lead developer on multiple large web projects.

Intermediate Full Stack Web Developer, Sony NZ, Auckland - 2000-2006

Design and development of multiple Sony branded customer, business and internal sites. Tasked with the management and updating of the internal Intranet & associated tools.

Education

Digital and Collaborative Teaching and Learning (micro credential), academyEx — Present

Search Inside Yourself — 2023

Assessment Practice Level 4, People Potential — 2021

Diploma in Business Computing,

Bay of Plenty Polytechnic — 1999

Skills

5 years development team management experience. 5 years hands on experience with ReactJS. 6 years combined experience using cloud technologies from Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services. Varied experience having worked for development shops, in house development teams and startups.

References

Available on request.

Personal Interests

- Running (road & trail) Longest race Tauranga Marathon 2022
- Mountain biking
- Performance conditioning and training